National Congress of Neighborhood Women Records, 1974-1999
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. PROGRAMS 1975-1996
  - Employment
    - Job Development Program
      - Workshops and courses
        - Census takers (recruitment and hiring), 1980-81 (Box 83, Folder 3-5)
        - Fundraising workshop, Bank Street College, 1979 (Box 83, Folder 6)
        - Fundraising workshop, undated (Box 83, Folder 7)
        - Job factory (Box 83, Folder 8)
        - Job Finding and Holding workshop, undated (Box 83, Folder 9)
        - Job Search workshop: correspondence, questionnaire, evaluation form, course outlines, handouts, forms, and notes, 1980-81 (Box 83, Folder 10-20)
        - Postal workers training, 1981 (Box 83, Folder 21)
        - Video workshop, 1981-82 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Employment and Training Program
      - General: descriptions, correspondence, meetings, planning material, funding material, and reports, 1981-83, undated (Box 84, Folder 1-14)
        [See also Job Development-General]
      - Publicity: flyers (Box 84, Folder 15)
      - Bus Shelters (Project Greenhope): correspondence and proposals, 1981-82 (Box 84, Folder 16-19)
        [See also Project Open Doors-Subcontractors]
      - Training programs
        - Childcare provider training: correspondence, proposals, notes, and course materials (Box 85, Folder 1-4)
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Support services]
        - Control Data Institute: correspondence, contract, proposal, policies, and printed material (Box 85, Folder 5-8)
        - Taylor Business Institute: correspondence, contract, policies, and printed material (Box 85, Folder 9-10)
      - World of Work (Box 85)
        [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Women's Public Works; and Public Housing Tenants Training]
      - General: publicity, descriptions, correspondence, reports, staff, and miscellaneous drafts and notes, 1985-87, undated (Box 85, Folder 11-16)
      - Course materials: agendas, forms, and handouts, 1985-86 (Box 85, Folder 17-18)
      - Trainings
        - Bank Street School, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 19-25)
        - Public Housing districts, 1985-86 (Box 85, Folder 26-28)
          [See also Housing and tenants-Public housing tenants training]
    - Resources
      [See also Resource Center]
      - Job Club (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Job development (Box 86, Folder 2-4)
      - N.O.W. NY (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - The Nuts and Bolts of N.T.O [ Non-Traditional Occupations] (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - N.Y.S. Department of Commerce (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Recruitment and Training Program (RTP) (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - S.U.N.Y. (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - TAP Centers (testing and placement) (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - Training programs (Box 86, Folder 11-12)
      - United Neighborhood Houses - Job Development Program (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Women's employment programs (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - WomanSpace-Career Counseling (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Work in America Institute (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1-7)
    - Training materials and manuals (Box 87, Folder 8-10)
  - Housing and tenants
    - Housing
      - Greenpoint Renaissance Enterprise Corporation-Neighborhood Women's Inter-generational Housing Project
        [See also ORGANIZATIONS-St. Nicholas Preservation and Housing Rehabiliatation Corp.; and Williamsburg/Greenpoint Community Planning Board]
        - Publicity (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Administration: proposals, reports, by-laws, contracts, finances, fundraising, regulations, 1984-1993, undated (Box 88, Folder 2-17)
        - Planning: correspondence, meetings, petitions, architects, construction, homeless, miscellaneous notes and drafts, 1983-91, undated (Box 88, Folder 18-25)
        - Resources and miscellaneous, 1983-90, undated (Box 88, Folder 26)
      - Habitat for Humanity: printed material, report, correspondence, meeting, and miscellaneous, 1985-86, undated (Box 88, Folder 27-32)
        [See also International]
      - Conferences
        - Housing as a Tool for Economic Development, St. Louis, 1983 (Box 89, Folder 1)
          [See also Tenants-Bertha Gilkey]
        - Housing Options for Women (H.O.W.), Camden, NJ, 1987
          [See also International-HABITAT; SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-National Planning Conference, 1986; and SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS]
          - Planning
            - General: articles, reports, printed material, and correspondence, 1986-87 (Box 89, Folder 2-3)
            - National Planning Committee: correspondence, meetings, finances, and miscellaneous, 1986-87 (Box 89, Folder 4-16)
            - Conference Advisory Boards, 1987 (Box 90, Folder 1-2)
            - International Planning Committee, 1987: correspondence, and meetings (Box 90, Folder 3)
            - Organizations
              - U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD): correspondence, proposal, grant, and report (Box 90, Folder 4-5)
              - United Nations Center for Human Settlements (Habitat) - HOW (Box 90, Folder 6)
              - Camden Urban Women's Center (Box 90, Folder 7)
              - N. J. State Department of Community Affairs Women's Division (Box 90, Folder 8)
              - Meetings by Design - Linda Brouard (Box 90, Folder 9)
            - Participants: correspondence, application, lists, and miscellaneous information (Box 90, Folder 10-12)
            - Pre-conference mailing to participants (Box 90, Folder 13)
            - Publicity: goals, brochure, letterhead, and press releases (Box 90, Folder 14-18)
            - Publicity (continued): film plans, and PR consultant (Box 91, Folder 1-2)
          - Co-Sponsors: correspondence and application responses (Box 91, Folder 3-5)
          - Mailings: brochure, bio request, and forms (Box 91, Folder 6-8)
          - Local arrangements (Box 91, Folder 9-10)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 11-13)
          - Conference
            - Conference packet (Box 91, Folder 14)
            - Keynote speakers (Box 91, Folder 15)
            - Entertainment: Sweet Honey in the Rock (Box 91, Folder 16)
            - Registration cards (Box 92, Folder 1-2)
          - Follow-up
            - General: correspondence, meetings, mailings, reports, and drafts, 1987-88 (Box 92, Folder 3-9)
            - "Count me in" mailings: replies and summary (Box 92, Folder 10)
            - Questionnaire (Box 92, Folder 11)
            - GROOTS: printed material and report, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 12-13)
            - Film Documentary with Susan Hamoritch (Box 92, Folder 14)
              [See also Publicity]
            - Models (Box 92, Folder 15)
          - Financial: correspondence, receipts, budgets, contributions, bills, and account information (Box 92, Folder 16-22)
      - Subject files
        - Papers (by NCNW staff and others)
          - "The Administration and the Older Tenant in Continued Occupancy," by Melvin Stepman (Box 93, Folder 1)
          - "At Home in the USA: Why Housing is Every Woman's Issue," by Leslie Kanes Weisman (Box 93, Folder 2)
          - "Background Paper on Single Parent Family Proposal," by Sharon Lauer (Box 93, Folder 3)
          - "Housing Displacement and Women," by Jean Peterman (Box 93, Folder 4)
          - "Housing, Business and Women's Organizations," by Joan Forrester Sprague (Box 93, Folder 5)
          - "Neighborhood Women Look at Housing," by Ronnie Feit and Jan Peterson (Box 93, Folder 6)
          - "Neighborhood Women's Agenda for Housing in New York State," by Ronnie Feit (Box 93, Folder 7)
          - "Neighborhood Women's Agenda for Economic Development in New York State," by Ronnie Feit (Box 93, Folder 7)
          - "Public Housing: What is Happening in Public Housing in the United States Today," author unknown (Box 93, Folder 8)
          - "Time for Action to Meet Women's Shelter Needs," by Ied Guinee (Box 93, Folder 9)
          - "Woman-Made America: The Case of Early Public Housing Policy," by Eugenie Ladder Birch (Box 93, Folder 10)
          - Brochure: "Our Practices: Women, Homes, and Community Super Coalition" (photocopy) (Box 93, Folder 11)
          - McAuley Institute: correspondence and printed material (Box 93, Folder 12)
          - Report: "Building and Dwelling on Women's Terms" (Box 93, Folder 13)
          - Report: "Problems of Homeless Women" (Box 93, Folder 14)
          - Summary: "Women and Housing: A Training Programme" (Box 93, Folder 15)
          - Testimony: "Women and Housing" (Box 93, Folder 16)
        - Clippings (Box 93, Folder 17)
        - Miscellaneous: printed material, and statistics (Box 93, Folder 18-20)
    - Public housing tenant programs
      - Administration
        - Community Service Society: organization, NCNW partnership, papers, printed material, proposals, contracts, and reports, 1984-88, undated (Box 94, Folder 1-17)
        - Community Service Society (continued): correspondence, meetings, finances, technical assistance, resources, and miscellaneous, 1985-89, undated (Box 95, Folder 1-20)
      - New York City Housing Authority
        - General: history, status of projects, report, NCNW agreement, proposal, reports, correspondence, and financial, 1984-87, undated (Box 96, Folder 1-10)
        - Procedures and regulations, 1980-86, undated (Box 96, Folder 11-15)
        - Tenants and management: individual cases, tenant patrol, and tenant participation training manual 1983-87, undated (Box 96, Folder 16-19)
        - Miscellaneous, 1986-87, undated (Box 96, Folder 20)
      - Employment specialist, Jesus Lorenzo: correspondence, memoranda, notes, publicity, and miscellaneous, 1986-87, undated (Box 96, Folder 21-22)
      - Public housing reports, 1986 (Box 96, Folder 23)
      - Tenant training and organizing
        [See also Employment and Women's Public Works]
        - General: concept proposal, report, 1986, undated (Box 97, Folder 1-2)
        - Bertha Gilkey
          - General: correspondence and proposals, 1984-88, undated (Box 97, Folder 3-5)
          - Training model, 1985-86, undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
          - Model communities
            - Cochran Gardens (St. Louis), 1985, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
            - Clarksdale (Louisville, Kentucky), 1985, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
            - Lakeview Terrace (Ohio), 1984-85, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
            - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 97, Folder 10)
          - Training schedules, 1985-86 (Box 97, Folder 11)
          - Meetings: agendas, attendance, minutes, publicity, tenant association elections, training sessions, leases, survey, evaluations, and miscellaneous, 1984-85, undated (Box 97, Folder 12-20)
          - Public Housing Training Conference (Wash D.C.), 1986 (Box 97, Folder 21)
          - Resources: printed material, 1986, undated (Box 97, Folder 22)
          - Miscellaneous, 1984-86, undated (Box 97, Folder 23)
        - Mildred Johnson (?): miscellaneous materials, 1983-85, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
        - Education and job training (Education and Employment Readiness Training program and (Jobs for the Future), 1985-86, undated (Box 98, Folder 2-4)
        - Other trainings, 1984-86, undated (Box 98, Folder 5-9)
      - Williamsburg/Greenpoint Federation of Public Housing Developments
        - General: correspondence, report, funding application, and by-laws, consultant, job descriptions, and memoranda, 1985-88, undated (Box 98, Folder 10-16)
        - Steering committee, 1985 (Box 98, Folder 17)
        - Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 98, Folder 18)
        - Melanie Beale (Coordinator): correspondence, contact lists, forms, newsletter, publicity, and notes, 1986-88, undated (Box 98, Folder 19-24)
        - Melanie Beale (continued): reports, students' work, time sheets and schedules, subject files, and miscellaneous, 1983-89, undated (Box 99, Folder 1-15)
        - Correspondence, 1985-88, undated (Box 99, Folder 16)
        - Events
          - Awards Dinner, 1986 (Box 99, Folder 17)
          - "Voices of Wisdom" Celebration and History of Five Black Women Leaders, 1988 (Box 99, Folder 18)
        - Fundraising, 1987 (Box 99, Folder 19)
        - Lists, 1986-88, undated (Box 99, Folder 20)
        - Meetings, 1985-88, undated (Box 100, Folder 1-4)
        - Politics
          - Area Policy Board elections, 1987-88 (Box 100, Folder 5)
          - Getting involved politically, undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
          - Legislation, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 7)
          - Voter registration: correspondence, lists, minutes, and Board of Elections registrations, 1988 (Box 100, Folder 8-9)
        - Tenant screening and NYCHA work requests, 1986-87, undated (Box 100, Folder 10-11)
      - Tenant associations
        - Borinquen Plaza correspondence, lists, minutes, notes, and petitions, 1982-88, undated (Box 101, Folder 1-4)
        - Bushwick/Hylan, 1986-88 (Box 101, Folder 5)
        - Cooper Park (Box 101)
          - General: map, newsletter, and clippings, 1986-87, undated (Box 101, Folder 6-8)
          - Administration: proposal, constitution, contracts, Executive Board, Advisory Committee, and finances, 1985-87, undated (Box 101, Folder 9-14)
          - Community Center, 1988, undated (Box 101, Folder 15)
          - Correspondence, 1983-88, undated (Box 101, Folder 16)
          - Employment, circa 1984 (Box 101, Folder 17)
          - List, undated (Box 101, Folder 18)
          - Maintenance requests, 1985-86 (Box 101, Folder 19)
          - Meetings, 1985-87 (Box 101, Folder 20)
          - Petition, undated (Box 101, Folder 21)
          - Tenant Patrol and Welcome Wagon Committee, 1988, undated (Box 101, Folder 22)
          - Workshops
            - General, 1985-86 (Box 101, Folder 23)
            - Crack and Parents on Crack, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 24)
          - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 101, Folder 25)
        - Independence House, 1986-89 (Box 101, Folder 26)
        - Williamsburg Houses, 1982-88 (Box 101, Folder 27)
        - East Harlem
          [See also SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL -Videotapes]
          - East River, 1985, undated (Box 101, Folder 28)
          - James Weldon Johnson, 1984-86, undated (Box 101, Folder 29)
          - Wagner House, 1986-87 (Box 101, Folder 30)
          - Tenants Association Organization of East Harlem
            - General: project summary, applications, proposals, correspondence, and meetings, 1993-96, undated (Box 101, Folder 31-39)
            - Recognition awards night, circa 1996 (Box 101, Folder 40)
      - Subject files
        - Community Outreach Partnership program, 1994-96 (Box 102, Folder 1)
        - Contacts and organizations, undated (Box 102, Folder 2)
        - Day Care, undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
        - Earned Income Disregards, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        - Form letters, 1984 (Box 102, Folder 5)
        - Health, 1985 (Box 102, Folder 6)
        - Housing court, 1986, undated (Box 102, Folder 7)
        - Housing unit staff initiatives, undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
        - H.U.D., 1978, 1995, undated (Box 102, Folder 9-11)
        - Institution for Mediation and Conflict Resolution (Box 102, Folder 12)
        - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 102, Folder 13)
        - Office of Employment Services, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 14)
        - Ownership transfer project, 1985 (Box 102, Folder 15)
        - Proprietary lease, undated (Box 102, Folder 16)
        - Rent control, undated (Box 102, Folder 17)
        - Tenants rights, undated (Box 102, Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-93, undated (Box 102, Folder 19-20)
  - International
    - General: descriptions, publicity, and correspondence, 1982-87, undated (Box 102, Folder 21-22)
    - GROOTS (Grassroots Organizations Operating Together in Sisterhood)
      - Chronological file: correspondence, memoranda, agendas, minutes, and notes, 1989-90 (Box 102, Folder 23-24)
      - Publicity: newsletter, articles, flyers, and memorabilia, 1989-96, undated (Box 102, Folder 25-26)
      - Reports, 1989-90 (Box 102, Folder 27)
      - Planning Committee, 1989-90 (Box 102, Folder 28)
        [See also Madras, India conference, below]
      - GROOTS Task Force International (GTFI) (includes International Planning Committee for Madras conference)
        - Meetings: agendas and minutes, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 29)
        - Outreach: correspondence, questionnaires, and mailing lists, 1988-90 (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
      - International Women's Conference, Madras, India: publicity, report, correspondence, and planning committee, 1985-90 (Box 103, Folder 3-6)
      - GROOTS "local country forums": reports, publicity, drafts
        - General (Box 103, Folder 7)
        - South Asia and South Pacific (Box 103, Folder 8)
        - Latin America (Box 103, Folder 9)
        - Canada (Box 103, Folder 10)
      - Planning for Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, China, 1995 (Box 103)
        [See also United Nations]
        - "Search for university" (Box 103, Folder 11)
        - "Platform for Action-USA GROOTS" (Caroline Pezzulo), 1994 (Box 103, Folder 12)
        - "Women, Homes, and Community Building" (workshop), 1996 (Box 103, Folder 13)
        - "Alt2-WID Meeting," 1995 (Box 103, Folder 14)
        - "Economic Reform and Gender Analysis" (panel paper): correspondence, drafts, printed material, 1995 (Box 103, Folder 15-16)
        - "TCDC proposal," 1994 (Box 103, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified papers and drafts (Box 103, Folder 18)
    - United Nations
      - General
        - Chronological file: correspondence, memoranda, and printed material, 1982-91, undated (Box 104, Folder 1-2)
        - Application for consultative status, 1984-86 (Box 104, Folder 3-5)
      - UN Development Fund for Women (UNIFEM) (Box 104, Folder 6-7)
      - UN Decade for Women
        - World Conference on the UN Decade for Women, 1980 (Box 104, Folder 8)
        - New York Regional Conference for Women, 1980 (Box 104, Folder 9)
        - New York City Symposium on Women and Development, Hunter College: program, background, proposal, goals, correspondence, meetings, registration and invitations, mailing lists, and printed material, 1985 (Box 104, Folder 10-20)
        - UN Decade for Women Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1985-86
          - Pre-Nairobi Strategy Conference, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 1)
          - Pre-Conference Consultation on the 1985 Conference: reports, and correspondence, 1984-86 (Box 105, Folder 2-3)
          - Preparation materials, 1975, 1984-85, undated (Box 105, Folder 4-5)
          - Nairobi Forum: reports, applications, publicity, applications, and miscellaneous, 1984-86 (Box 105, Folder 6-8)
          - Conference follow-up
            - Beyond Nairobi (National Women's Conference Committee), 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
            - NCNW follow-up, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
            - Equity 2000: Meeting the Nairobi Challenge, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous
          - "International Women's Decade and Beyond (meeting): printed material, notes, and correspondence, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 12)
          - UN Convention on the Elimination of all Forms of Discrimination against Women: printed material (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, China, 1995
        - General, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 14-15)
        - NGO Planning Committee, 1994 (Box 105, Folder 16)
        - Preparation materials, 1994 (Box 105, Folder 17-18)
        - GROOTS and NCNW planning: general, task force, report, tent, and miscellaneous, 1994-95, undated (Box 105, Folder 19-23)
          [See also GROOTS]
      - HABITAT International
        [See also Housing-Conferences]
        - General: correspondence, reports, and publicity, 1985-86 (Box 106, Folder 1-2)
        - "Bringing HABITAT Home" campaign (Box 106, Folder 3)
        - HABITAT II: report, and printed material, circa 1995 (Box 106, Folder 4-6)
        - International Year of the Shelter for the Homeless, 1987 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous meetings and conferences
        - Women and Power (5th National Women in Crisis Conference), 1984 (Box 106, Folder 8)
        - Women and Shelter conference, Vienna, 1985 (Box 106, Folder 9-10)
        - Women in Development meeting: notes, and printed material, undated (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Subjects
      - Africa (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - Boulding, Elise: article (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - European study trips (Italy, Poland, Germany), 1980-84 (Box 106, Folder 15-17)
      - German Marshall Fund (Box 107, Folder 1-3)
        [See also Netherlands-Ied Guinee]
      - Grassroots Initiatives and Strategies (GRIS) conference, 1982 (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - India (includes Working Women's Forum) (Box 107, Folder 5-6)
      - Israel (Box 107, Folder 7-8)
      - Japan (Box 107, Folder 9)
      - Latin America (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - Mobility International (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - National Conference on Women, The Economy and Public Policy, 1984 (Box 107, Folder 12)
      - Netherlands (includes Ied Guinee) (Box 107, Folder 13-16)
      - Nicaragua (Box 107, Folder 17)
      - Operation Crossroads (Box 107, Folder 18)
      - Overseas Education Fund (OEF) (Box 107, Folder 19)
      - Percy Amendment (Box 107, Folder 20)
      - Philippines, undated (Box 107, Folder 21)
      - Posters (Box 107, Folder 22)
        [See Oversized material]
      - Putamayo (Box 107, Folder 23)
      - Tree Project, 1983 (Box 107, Folder 24)
      - Trickle Up Program, Inc., 1983 (Box 107, Folder 25)
      - Tunisia, 1984 (Box 107, Folder 26)
      - "Women in the City" (OECD conference), 1994 (Box 107, Folder 27)
      - World Bank/IMF ("Fifty Years is Enough"), 1994 (Box 107, Folder 28)
  - Leadership
    [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Individuals-Lisel Burns; and OVERSIZED MATERIAL]
    - General
      - Goals and objectives, 1983-84, undated (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Interview with Jan Peterson and Bertha Gilkey, 1983 (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - Publicity: printed material, drafts, and notes, 1981-83, undated (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Administration
      - Project abstracts and proposals, 1980-84, undated (Box 108, Folder 4-13)
      - Reports, 1981-87 (Box 108, Folder 14-22)
      - Staff: job descriptions, profiles, meetings, work plans, lists, memoranda, notes, and questionnaires, undated (Box 109, Folder 1-9)
      - Affiliate leaders, 1980-84, undated (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - Financial, 1981-83, undated (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Training materials: models, manual, guidelines, handouts, charts, drafts, printed material, and notes, 1983-93, undated (Box 109, Folder 12-18)
      [See also Support groups]
    - Local training
      - Leadership Training Course, New York City, 1979
        - General: correspondence, minutes, and memoranda (Box 110, Folder 1)
        - Workshops (Box 110, Folder 2-10)
        - Questionnaire (Box 110, Folder 11-13)
        - "Be Yourself and More" video project: draft script, budget, and release forms (Box 110, Folder 14-16)
          [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Development-WEEA]
        - Miscellaneous: printed material and drafts, 1979, undated (Box 110, Folder 17-18)
      - Leadership Training, New York City, 1981-82
        - General: descriptive correspondence, meetings, applications (completed), and participant lists (Box 110, Folder 19-21)
        - Trainings: agendas, notes, handouts, and lists (Box 110, Folder 23-26)
        - City-wide leadership support group/network (Box 110, Folder 27-28)
      - Leadership Skills Training Series, 1982 (Box 110, Folder 29)
      - Williamsburg-Greenpoint Neighborhood Women's annual leadership retreats
        - 1982-84 (Box 111, Folder 1-24)
        - 1985 (Box 112, Folder 1-7)
      - Neighborhood Women Spring Leadership Training Day, 1987 (Box 112, Folder 8)